主啊  女士们
My lords, and ladies.
今天你们的王后就要选出她的勇士
Today your queen will choose her champion.
此刻  他不仅将为了她的荣耀而战
Here, he will battle for not only her honor,
也将为他自己的头衔而战
but for a title of his own.
但只有打败我的侍卫长
But only if he can defeat the Captain of my guard,
黑爵士  贺拉斯
Sir Horace the Black!
威廉姆爵士
Sir William...
你愿意为了我的荣耀而战么
Would thou fight for my honor?
直至战死  王后殿下
To the death, your majesty.
让我们祈祷不至于此  好吗
Let's hope it does not come to that, eh?
我选择威廉姆爵士为我的勇士
I choose Sir William as my champion.
攻击他的左侧
Attack from his left side.
今早我看到他的侍卫在包扎肩部
I saw his squire bandaging that shoulder this morning.
我祝你好运  赐你力量
I wish thee luck and strength.
我感到需要全部我能得到的
I feel I shall need all I can get.
我的侍卫长
The Captain of my guard
黑爵士  贺拉斯
Sir Horace the Black!
我的王后  你确定不再考虑你的选择吗
Are you sure you wouldn't like to reconsider your choice, my queen?
我相信我的选择是正确的  国王
I believe I chose rightly, my king.
勇敢骑士们 以这片土地光荣的传统  现在开始
Brave knights, in the honored tradition of our lands, have at ye!
我觉得你选错了  亲爱的
I feel you chose most poorly, my love.
威廉姆  威廉姆
William! William!
威廉姆
William?
怎么了
What is it?
你的眼睛
Your eyes.
威廉姆
William?
要辆救护车  卡姆登游乐场
We need an ambulance at the Camden Fairgrounds.
你是新来的
You're new.
你没穿衣服
You're naked.
另外  声明一下有点冷
And, for the record, a little bit cold.
抱歉  我不知道有人在家
I'm sorry, I didn't know that anyone was home.
詹姆斯上早班  我也马上要走
James had an early call, and I was just leaving.
不吃早饭吗
Without breakfast?
我没事  谢谢
I'm fine, thanks.
我是山姆  顺便说一下
I'm Sam, by the way.
豪斯  很高兴认识你
House. Nice to meet you.
要是你能穿上这个就更好了
It'd be nicer if you'd put this on.
那么  你和威尔森
So you and Wilson...
以为你昨晚呆在纽约了
thought you were staying in New York last night.
对不起 一定是没看到外面的"请勿打扰" 了
Sorry, must have missed the "if this trailer be a-rockin" sign out front.
我真的晚了 要是可以假装什么也没发生
I'm really late, so if there's any chancethat we can pretend this never happened,
我完全没有意见
I'd be completely fine with that.
8岁小孩  耳朵流血
An eight-year-old with bleeding ears.
我马上就能看你耳朵流血 再你给个彻底的肌肉退化
I'll see your bleeding ears and raise you a total muscular degeneration.
搞什么
What the hell?
我曾做过这样的梦
I had a dream like this once.
结果可不妙
It didn't end well.
好啊  我忠诚的农夫们
Huzzah, my loyal peasants!
豪斯  你在干什么
House, what are you doing?
在戈尔茨坦[诺贝尔医学奖]的割礼中代替山谬尔·拉比
Filling in for Rabbi Shmuhl at the Goldstein bris.
我忙的时候
While I'm busy,
你们能去看看楼下急症里的骑士
you all can check out the Knight down in the E.R.,
没有夺得王冠  癫痫却发作了
who, instead of seizing the throne, just seized.
他在文艺复兴艺术节上工作吗
He works at a Renaissance Festival?
不在那里工作  他住在那里 作为小剧团
Doesn't work there, he lives there as part of a wonderful little troupe,
于周末时重现伟大的时代
who spend their weekends reenacting a nobler age,
当人们随地解手时
when people crapped in the streets,
十三会是一个祖母
and thirteen would have been a grandmother.
是数周  不是周末
Weeks, not weekends.
这里写着  他已经露营一个月了
Says here he's been camping out for a month.
用笔试试看
Try doing that with a pen.
在你杀了我们中的一个前 为何不把那个放下呢
Why don't you put that down before you kill one of us?
更好的主意 为何不给我点有用的东西
Better idea, why don't you give me something I can use
那样就没必要了
so I won't feel the need to?
争斗后的癫痫发作显然提示脑震荡
Seizure right after a fight obviously suggests concussion.
显然  不是不然急诊不会找豪斯
Obviously it isn't, or the E.R. wouldn't have called House.
全套盔甲能防止明显外伤
A full set of armor would protect againt visible trauma,
但不能防止可传递震荡力
but not transmitted concussive force.
可能是硬膜下血肿
Could be a subdural hematoma.
你们忘了魔鬼附体了
You're forgetting to demonize.
恶魔  邪恶的硬膜下血肿
An evil, satanic subdural hematoma.
不是
No.
两只恶魔的眼睛
Two demon eyes.
巩膜出血
Hemorrhaging in the sclerae.
可能是对文艺复兴文艺节上的东西过敏
Could be an allergic reaction to something from the Renaissance Fair.
因此我们要检查一下中世纪
Which is why we need to check out middle earth.
福曼  带上佛罗多[魔戒人物]和霍比人[魔戒人物]分享面包
Foreman, take Frodo and break bread with the Hobbits.
我仍然认为血肿更有可能
I still think a hematoma is more likely.
所以你和奇斯去做核磁共振
That's why you and Chase are gonna get an MRI.
但你刚
But you just--
我说了佛罗多  不是咕噜[指环王人物]
I said Frodo, not Gollum.
他是说我腿短吗 或者是脚上多毛吗
Is he saying I have short legs or hairy feet?
我都不知道谁是佛罗多
I don't even know who Frodo is.
那个小妞是谁  为什么要藏着
Who's the chick, and why are you hiding her?
昨晚你在家吗
You were home last night?
还有今早
And this morning.
我撞见你的宝贝  光着
I bumped into your babe, naked.
我告诉过你别进我的浴室
I told you to stay out of my bathroom.
我在厨房
I was in the kitchen.
她没穿衣服在厨房吗
She was naked in the kitchen?
我没穿
I was naked.
你为什么不穿衣服去厨房
Why the hell were you naked in the kitchen?
眼下这个不重要了
Uh, it's not important right now.
重要的是  为何一开始你就不想我见她
What is, is why you didn't want me to meet her in the first place.
她结婚了吗 没有
Is she married?  No.
是病人吗
A patient?
我没时间谈这个
I don't have time for this.
她过去是男的
She used to be a man.
豪斯
House!
她想成为一个男的
She wants to be a man.
山姆  是一个男人的名字  全称是
Sam--it's a man's name, short for...
萨曼莎
Samantha.
我们相遇前你娶过的没有灵魂的女妖
The soulless harpy you were married to before we met.
人是会变的  豪斯
People change, House.
当然  变老  卵巢开始枯竭
Sure. They get older, ovaries start drying up,
如你般的好男人会焕发第二春
and nice guys like you look attractive again.
听着  我了解  在你的疯狂的想法中
Listen, I know that, in your own demented way,
你觉得  你在帮我留心
you think you're looking out for me.
但是我的事
But I have this.
说到你的事  你的意思是 心中感到低落么
By this, you mean a sinking feeling in the pit of the stomach.
行了  我懂
Fine. I get it.
是你的人生  你去搞砸吧
It's your life. You go screw it up.
我能等  等什么
I can wait.For what?
等着告诉你"我早说过"
To tell you, "I told you so."
没有血肿迹象
No signs of hematoma.
脑部看上去完全正常
Brain looks completely normal.
一切正常  除了一个方面 他喜欢玩角色扮演
Normal, except for the fact that he likes to play dress-up.
我叔叔曾经假装他是利奥波德之王
My Uncle used to pretend he was King Leopold.
我不是在假装
I'm not pretending.
不好意思
Um, sorry about that.
你不会是真把自己当成是个骑士吧
You don't really think you're a Knight, do you?
骑士生涯并不是一场游戏
Being a Knight isn't a game.
这是一种生活格调
It's a lifestyle,
我们每天都以这种方式生活着  而不是只在角色扮演时才这么干
and we do it every day,not just when we play dress-up.
我们有着生活准则  坚持美好的信念
We live by a code and uphold ideals
比如忠诚  勇气  谦逊
like loyalty, courage, humility.
那么你们穿着盔甲  互相往死里打也算是其中的一种喽
And the part where you beat the crap out of each other in armor?
那只是我们为了娱乐才作的
That we do for fun.
至少到昨天为止还是这么回事
At least it was up until yesterday.
我们是不是快结束了
Are--are we almost done?
因为我感觉有点
'Cause I'm feeling--
我们得在他呕吐之前把他弄出来
let's get him out of there before he aspirates.
核磁共振有没有检查出什么异常呢
anything abnormal on the MRI?
天哪
God's teeth,
这些衣服着实古怪
what strange manner of garments be these?
好  我们很快就回去
Okay, we'll be back soon.
此男还手握此等微小异怪之物
He consorts with tiny demons in his hand.
此乃巫蛊之物
'Tis witchcraft, I say!
我看起来像是到这里来陪你们玩得吗
Do I look like I'm here to play pretend with you?
放轻松  他们不是在针对你
Relax, it's not personal.
你可以告诉他们你是穿梭时空的旅行者之类的谎话
Just tell them you're a time traveler or something.
可是  既然我们都已经来了 不如就好好享受一下
Well, if we're gonna be here, we might as well enjoy it.
我们的骑士大人刚刚在核磁共振器里吐了
Our Knight just vomited inside the MRI.
陶博认为他可能是食物中毒
Taub thinks it might be food poisoning...
这也难怪
which shouldn't be surprising--
露天公厕  在牲畜棚旁
outdoor latrines, food prep going on
处理食物
next to livestock.
吾闻尔等欲问威廉姆骑士之事
I hear you wish to speak with me,
他可安好 不是太好
concerning Sir William. How faireth he? Not well,
不然我们也不会到这里来
or we wouldn't be here.
真乃顽疾是也
A pox indeed is--
迈尔斯  [别装古人说话了]
Miles.
我们还以为只是脑震荡
We just thought it was a concussion.
他会好起来吧
He's gonna be okay, right?
我们需要查看一下他宿营的地方
We need to look at the area he was camping out in.
你也许需要在这个王国里搞个全民护牙计划
And you might want to invest into a dental plan for the kingdom.
你确定他是从这里得的病吗
You sure he got sick from something here?
我们现在还无法断言  但是
We're not sure of anything yet, but...
你认为这是什么
What do you make of this?
看起来像是呕吐物
Hmm... looks like vomit.
这就说明他在决斗前就已经显示出病症了
Means he was showing symptoms prior to the fight.
没错  可我指的是这个
True, but I meant this.
噢  这是个牛眼
Oh, it's a cow eye.
是比武大赛的前夜大餐
From the night before the tournament.
他让骑士们吃各种各样恶心的东西
He makes the Knights eat all kinds of disgusting stuff.
为什么
Why?
他是从恐惧元素那个节目里得来的灵感
He got the idea from Fear Factor.
他怎么在入院时没有提起呢
Why didn't he mention it when he checked into the hospital?
我让他们发誓对这个仪式保密的
I make them all take an oath of secrecy about the ritual.
威廉姆非常认真地扮演 地对待骑士这个角色
William tends to take his role as a Knight very seriously.
你认为这是导致他昏迷的原因吗
Do you think that's what caused him to pass out?
这可一点都不卫生
That's not exactly sanitary.
有趣的东西从来都不卫生
Fun stuff never is.
极为严重的细菌性感染食物中毒可以解释癫痫和呕吐病症
Serious bacterial food poisoning explains seizure and vomiting.
做个腰椎穿刺可以证实这点
A lumbar puncture could confirm.
可是这不是食物中毒
Except it's not food poisoning.
如果是的话急诊室现在就会像亚瑟王的宫殿般繁华了
If it was, the E.R. Would look like Camelot right now.
要想引起食物中毒 你只需要吃个腐坏的眼球
All it takes is one bad eyeball.
或是睾丸 牛脑  或是我的个人推荐
Or testicle, cow brain, or my personal favorite,
猪肠子加上括约肌作
pig rectum, with a side order
佐菜
of sphincter.
我想在澳洲人们叫这种食物为早餐
I think they call that breakfast in Australia.
没人因此得病
No one else was sick,
那是因为他们不像他那么过敏
because they weren't allergic like he was.
对什么过敏
To what?
这就是我需要把你送到地心去找寻的东西
That's what I sent you to middle earth to find out.
用你取回的样本去做个划痕试验
Run scratch tests for the samples you brought back.
那需要花时间  而他的状况正在变糟
That's gonna take time, and he's getting worse.
那就先给他上肾上腺素
So treat him with epinephrine too.
这个应该能阻止新病症的出现
This should prevent any more symptoms
我们就有足够的时间来找出你的过敏源
until we can figure out what it is you're allergic to.
多谢
Thanks.
我告诉过你不该把那些东西都吃了
Told you you shouldn't have eaten all that stuff.
你真的不用待在这里
You know, you don't have to stay.
我知道你和迈尔斯为了处理婚礼
I'm sure you and Miles are crazy busy,
和相关的事情都快忙疯了
what with the wedding and all.
迈尔斯说我们会把婚礼延期到
Miles said we could postpone it until--
别担心  我会好起来的
don't worry. I'll be fine.
我会出席你们婚礼的
I'll be there.
我只希望你们能找个好的摄影师
I just hope you have a good photographer,
我可不觉得普通摄影师能够处理好我的这个红眼问题
'cause I don't think the standard red-eye filter is gonna work on these.
把右臂伸出来
I need your right arm.
那个
That, uh...
觉得
Feels--
我感觉有点奇怪
feels strange.
怎么了  哪儿不对
What is it? What's wrong?
他的心跳变的不规律了
His heart rate's become irregular.
我胸口疼  我觉得它就要炸开了
My--my chest hurts. It feels like it's gonna explode.
心动过速  我们要把心跳击回正常频率
Tachycardia--we need to shock him back into rhythm.
天哪  威廉姆
Oh, my God, William.
把他的上衣揭开
I need his gown open.
这  这是什么东西
What is-- what is that stuff?
我不知道
I don't know.
这绝对不是过敏
It's definitely not an allergy,
不然肾上腺素应该缓解症状而不是加剧症状
or the eppy would have helped him, not made him worse.
除非他既是过敏生病 又对对治疗药剂亚硫酸氢钠过敏
Unless he's allergic and allergic to the cure.Sodium bisulfite--
肾上腺素药品中的能使药物快速生效
the preservative that keeps eppy peppy--
的添加剂会导致心动过速
can cause tachycardia.
预激综合征一样会导致心动过速
So can wolff-parkinson-white syndrome,
它还会引起眼部充血
and it also causes hemorrhaging in the eyes.
以及心电通道异常
And abnormal electrical pathways in the heart,
继而引起癫痫
which could cause seizures.
但它不会引起皮肤感染
But not skin infections.
有一种感染
There is an infection that can cause
会引起皮肤和神经损伤  而且迅速传播 并无法医治
skin and neurological damage and spreads rapidly without treatment.
耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌[MRSA]
Methicillin resistant staphylococcus aureus?
我们的骑士感染了MRSA
Lord have MRSA.
你在把他心脏电击回正常心率时 没有带手套
You weren't wearing gloves when we shocked his heartback into rhythm.
我确信你会没事的
I'm sure you'll be fine.
你们两个带着样本到实验室去确认
You two get a sample to the lab to confirm,
你带骑士去隔离病房给他静脉注射抗生素
you get the Knight into isolation and on I.V. Antibiotics.
你  离我远一点
You... stay away from me.
我们需要谈一下
Need to talk.
关于MRSA吗  我都知道了  我们
About the MRSA? I know, we're--
不是什么MRSA不MRSA的
MRSA, shmrsa.
是些重要的事你是指那些你认为是比
Something important. Something you think is more important
那些可以像野火般传遍整个医院的
than the potentially lethal bacteria
致命细菌更为重要的事
spreading like wildfire through my hospital?
那么范围就已经缩小到 那些有关私人的  愚蠢的事情了
Well, that narrows it down to something personal and stupid.
威尔森
Wilson.
刚好证实了我的理论
Theory confirmed.
他在和他的第一任妻子约会  我知道
He is dating his first wife. I know.
我不信
I don't believe it.
你不信他居然没有先征得你的同意吗
That he didn't ask your permission first?
不  我惊讶的是他竟然有事情能瞒住我
No, that he's actually capable of keeping a secret from me.
是么  威尔森没告诉你的事情可多着呢
Well, you'd be surprised how many things Wilson doesn't tell you.
真的
Would I?
比如  你和你爸最好的朋友 上床的事吗
Like... Like how you slept with your father's best friend or...
他死定了
I'm gonna kill him.
你得劝他们分手
You need to break them up.
没门
Forget it.
你就打算袖手旁观等着看那金发魔鬼故伎重演
So you'd rather sit back and watch while the evil blonde gorges on Wilson's tender flesh
再把威尔森敏感的心撕成碎片吗
and then tosses out his bones like she did the last time?
你记得他跟她分手之后的样子吧
You remember what he was like after that?
我记得
Yes, I do.
这就是了  行动吧
Well, then do something.
天知道  我怎么劝他都不会听
God knows he's not gonna listen to me.
你则不然  与各种烂人恋爱交往了
You, on the other hand, have decades of experience
几十年  经验丰富
dating and being attracted to losers.
明显  我不在其列
Obviously, I don't include myself. You know what happens
干预他人情感生活是什么后果  你清楚得很
when you interfere in other people's relationships?
自然  我是惯犯
Of course. I do it all the time.
明白你的意思了
Hmm, I see your point.
所以我才不闻不问
That is why I'm staying out of this.
强扭的瓜不甜
You force him to choose, you might not like the answer.
他看起来不那么痛苦了
He doesn't seem to be in as much pain anymore.
那太好了
That's good, but we won't be
但在疱疹消失前
out of the woods for sure
还不算完全脱离危险
until the blisters start to recede.
我好渴
Hey, I'm really thirsty.
帮我拿杯苏打水好吗
You mind getting me a soda?
好  我马上回来
Sure, I'll be right back.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我胸口疼得更厉害了
The pain in my chest, it's getting worse.
刚开始疼吗
Just now?
早开始了  只是不想让她担心
No, I didn't want to worry her.
你暗恋她多久了
So how long have you been in love with her?
什么
What?
不是的  我们只是朋友
No, we're just friends.
真的
Seriously.
从我第一次见她开始
Since the first time I saw her.
为什么不表白
Why don't you tell her?
-她跟我朋友订婚了  -国王吗
- She's engaged to my friend. - The King?
没见他来照顾你呢
Haven't seen him visiting or sitting by your bedside.
-他有职责在身  -是吧
- He has responsibilities. - Yeah.
王后不是也有职责
I'm guessing the Queen does too.
抢朋友的未婚妻  那算什么骑士
What kind of Knight steals his friend's bride?
我为自己有这种想法感到羞耻
I hate that I even think about it.
你不是骑士
You're not a Knight.
只是个普通人
You're just a guy.
可我有更高的追求
But I want to be more than that.
嗷
Oh!
胸口疼吗 不  是后背
Your chest?  No, my...my back.
像刀子扎的一样
Feels like there's a knife in it.
是不是感染扩散了
Is the infection spreading?
不是耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
It's not MRSA.
看上去像某种梭菌菌体
It looks like some sort of clostridial organism.
问题是  是哪种梭菌
Question is, which type of clostridium?
梭菌有几百种
There's hundreds.
产气荚膜梭菌吗
C. Perfringens?
与他的其他症状不符
Wouldn't account for his other symptoms.
破伤风杆菌呢
C. Tetani, on the other hand...
他应该注射过破伤风疫苗
Tetanus, he...he would have been inoculated against it.
那就是他割伤了但没打后续疫苗
So he cut himself and didn't get a booster shot.
这是个会拿剑跟人打架玩的家伙
The guy fights people with swords for fun.
能聪明到哪儿去
No one said he's smart.
他们打架不止是玩
They don't just fight for fun.
也为了证明自己的勇敢
They fight to prove their bravery.
你真信荣誉那套吗
You're buying this honor stuff?
打架可不是勇敢  是愚蠢
Fighting's not brave. It's just stupid.
你这么想倒不奇怪
You would say that.
你以为我没打过架吗
You think I've never been in a fight?
不  我只是觉得你没打赢过
No, I just think you've never won one.
我上大学的时候一挑三
I took on three guys in college once.
希望你们有叫人带买晚餐
Hope they bought you dinner first.
不是耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
It's not MRSA.
我知道  是毒葛
I know, it's poison Ivy.
毒葛
Poison Ivy?
反映严重者可能起疱疹
A severe reaction could cause the blisters
而对眼部刺激强烈可能诱发出血
and maybe irritate his eyes enough to cause the hemorrhaging,
但胸部疼痛和突发症候
but the chest pain and seizures...
他们每晚都生篝火
They have bonfires every night.
燃烧的枝叶将毒葛散布到空气中
The burning leaves aerosolizes the oil.
依照他体表受害症状
We've seen what it's done to the outside of his body.
不难想象他鼻窦和肺部受到的伤害
Imagine what it's doing to his lungs and his sinuses.
好吧  勉强说得通  但我还是
Okay, maybe it remotely fits, but I'd rather go
觉得科学依据比你的直觉可信
with scientific evidence than with your gut.
这个算不算
How about this?
明显  他的剑上也沾满了
Apparently, it's all over his sword.
又是心率
It's his heart rate again.
有多快
How fast is it?
心跳变缓  你怎么没带... 不是MRSA
It's slowing, why aren't you... It's not MRSA.
我要给他注射12毫升肾上腺素
I'm giving him 12 ccs epinephrine.
他肾上腺素过敏  他的心脏会跳爆的
He tested positive. You'll blow his heart out!
心跳再缓  就要停跳了
If it slows any more, it's gonna stop.
我就说嘛
I told you.
And I told you.
病源不是毒葛
That wasn't caused by poison Ivy.
也不是肾上腺素
Or epinephrine.
之前排除的心脏症候
That means the heart problem we ruled out,
要重新纳入考虑范围
we now have to rule back in.
我们在皮肤样本中发现了梭菌
We found clostridium bacteria in the skin samples.
泥土中就含有梭菌 它们基本是无害的
Clostridium's in dirt and basically harmless.
如果他免疫系统失灵的话也不是没有可能
But opportunistic, if his immune system is depressed.
白血病吗  那他在文艺复兴节前很久
Leukemia? He would have had symptoms way before
就该有症状了
the Renaissance Festival.
任何损害免疫体系的疾病都该有先期症状
Which is true of anything that would compromise his immune system,
所以一定是另有环境毒素在作怪
which means it has to be some other environmental toxin.
昨日的健康骑士今天就变了睡美人\
Yesterday he was a healthy Knight, Ntoday he's sleeping beauty.
没其他可能病症了吗
Nothing else fits?
食用带卵肉类感染旋毛虫病吗
Trichinosis from eating infected meat?
食物中毒的可能已经排除了
We already ruled out food poisoning.
我们查了肉铺和小吃摊
Both the butcher shop and the food stands
那集市卫生得很
at the fair were totally clean.
这么说  毒苹果必是来自他处了
Then he ate the poison apple somewhere else.
或者是你们没发现
Or maybe you just missed it.
开始按旋毛虫病治疗
Start treatment for trichinosis
做肌肉活检来验证
and confirm with a muscle biopsy.
难以置信我会开这个口
I can't believe I'm about to say this.
-山姆  -我就说嘛
- Sam... - Told you so.
不  她没甩我
No, she didn't dump me.
她想进一步地了解你
She wants to get to know you better.
该死
Damn it.
就不该让她看见我裸体
I never should have let her see me naked.
我所有的本能都告诉我不行
It goes against all my instincts,
可我还是答应她了
but I said all right.
为什么
Why?
她认为我不想让你见到她
She thinks I was hiding her from you.
没错啊
You were.
我可不想承认
I don't want her to know.
这么说  你是求我容忍一段建立在谎言
So you're asking me to condone a relationship
怀疑之上的交往
based on lies and mistrust.
是
Yeah.
几点  在哪儿见
When and where?
今晚8点  威尼斯餐馆
Tonight, Venezia, 8:00.
我穿什么去呢
What am I gonna wear?
我的正装可全送洗衣店了
All my cereal boxes are at the cleaners.
豪斯  听我说
House, listen.
我知道你在为我担心
I know you're worried about me,
也知道这种无私的关怀
and I also know that that kind of unselfishness
你不是对谁都如此有感而发
doesn't come naturally to you.
但我不想要你帮我
But I don't want your help.
我不需要你的帮助
I don't need your help.
就是来吃个饭
Just come to dinner
随意就好
and be your usual selfish self.
我怎能拒绝呢
How could I say no?
迈尔斯说他一会儿会顺便过来看你
Miles said he'd stop by later.
不  让他别来
No, tell him not to.
我不想让他看见这样的我
I don't want to be seen like this.
你病了  没什么好难为情的
You're sick. That's nothing to be ashamed of...
除非你意思是想让我走
Un-unless you're saying you want me to leave.
不  别走
No, don't.
我想他意思是
I think he's saying
和你在一起会好些  夏伦
it's different with you, Shannon.
男人们就是这样  他们不喜欢在同性面前显示出软弱的一面
It's a guy thing--they don't like showing weakness in front of each other.
对吗  威廉姆
Right, William?
没错
Right.
可能等我好点就会了
Maybe when I'm feeling a little better.
我准备从你这里取一小片肌肉组织试样
I'm gonna take a small sample of your muscle tissue here.
不介意到外面等一下吧
Do you mind waiting outside for this?
别伤着他
Don't hurt him.
放心吧
He's safe with me.
我以为你要告诉她
I thought you were gonna tell her.
我可没有权利说  但如果你需要
It's not my call, but if you ask me,
她也等着你说呢
she's waiting for you too.
骑士理应是无私的
Knights are supposed to be selfless.
没错  他们攻城略地  保家卫国
Right, they conquered countries and built Castles
是无私驱动的
by being selfless.
勇敢和忠诚是军人最好的品质
Bravery and loyalty are great qualities for soldiers.
如果你想成为国王
If you want to be King,
有时你该取你之所取
sometimes you have to be willing to take what's yours.
她不是我的
She's not mine.
也不是他的
She's not his either...
还不是
Not yet.
不过是一顿饭  放松点
It's just dinner. Relax.
相信我  没有"不过"当豪斯来搅局的时候
Trust me, there is no "just" when House is involved.
我们坐在一个餐厅的正中央
We're in the middle of a restaurant.
他还能...
What could he possibly...
干什么
Do?
看吧
That.
对不起  我们迟到了
Sorry we're late.
但你们知道  女人嘛
But you know girls.
出门前总要梳妆打扮一番
Always fiddling with the hair and the makeup.
詹姆斯  山姆  这位是萨拉
James, Sam.... this is Sarah.
-认识你们很高兴  -贺拉斯告诉我
- It's nice to meet you. - Horace has told me all--
是豪斯
House.
豪斯  总跟我提起你们俩
House... has told me all about you.
很高兴见到你们
It's nice to meet you.
诊断出什么病了吗
What's the diagnosis?
他的肌肉活检没问题
His muscle biopsy is clean.
不是旋毛虫病
It's not trichinosis.
豪斯错了  不是环境的问题
House was wrong, this is not environmental.
或者是我们错了  或者是在文艺复兴城落掉了某些细节
Or we screwed up and missed something at the Renaissance Fair.
你觉得我们落掉什么了吗
You think we did?
不  但豪斯会认为我们落下了
No, but I think House will think we did.
我们会落下什么呢
What could we have missed?
霉菌感染
Fungal infection?
他血液里一点都没有霉菌感染的迹象
There's nothing in his blood work even remotely suggesting that.
那他的症状是怎么回事
What if it's his symptoms?
你想重新检验我们用来检验孢子的样本吗
You wanna re-test every sample we took for spores?
我们会整晚都在这
We'll be here all night.
你注意到他最近有多痛苦吗
Have you noticed how much pain he's been in lately?
这又有什么关系呢
And that's relevant how?
额外的痛苦表明有额外的问题
Extra pain means extra cranky,
表明破坏了他的游戏规则
it means off his game.
除非我们让他别无选择否则他是不会承认不是环境问题的
He's not gonna accept this isn't environmental unless we give him no choice.
我真不敢相信你来自布鲁明顿
I cannot believe you're from Bloomington.
我知道  这难道不惊奇吗
I know, isn't it amazing?
是啊  多有意思啊
Yeah, delightful.
别理他
Ignore him.
他就是因为我们高兴而不高兴了
He's just upset that we're having fun.
你记得那个小面包店吗 有超好吃纸杯蛋糕的那个吗
Do you remember that little bakery, the one with the amazing cupcakes?
-基诺家  -没错
- Gino's. --Oh, yes!
每次我回家去的第一站
First stop, every time I go home.
我也是
Oh, me too...Mmm!
记得那个脱衣舞夜总会吗
Remember that strip club?
我以前还在那里工作过呢
Girl, I used to work at that strip club.
哪里疼  威廉姆
Where does it hurt, William?
我的腿  像着火了一样
My legs, it feels like they're on fire!
横肌纹溶解症表明他的肾脏正在衰竭
Rhabdomyolysis means his kidneys are failing.
也说明不是环境的问题
Also means it's not environmental.
我们得继续排查
We need to move on.
我建议先做全套的癌症检查
I recommend we start with a full cancer workup,
豪斯
House...
他的症状明显是环境...
His symptoms fit an environmental--
检测结果不是  我们重新...
the test results don't, we redid--
去检查公寓
search the apartment.
他三周没去过公寓了
He hasn't been there in three weeks--
快去
go!
现在
Now!
我还是喜欢他吃维科丁的时候
I liked him better when he was on Vicodin.
你和13去检查他家
You and thirteen check out his place.
在你们浪费时间的时候 我们去给他肝脏做超声波检查
While you're wasting your time, we'll ultrasound the liver.
如果是癌症  开始随便治疗
If it's cancer, it's as good a place as any to start.
我听说豪斯见过山姆了
I hear House met Sam.
第一次  他全裸着
First time, he was naked.
第二次  他带了个人妖妓女来吃饭
The second time he brought a transvestite prostitute to dinner.
总体来说  再糟糕不过了
Overall, it could have been worse.
很好
Great.
你就这反应吗
That's your reaction?
什么
What?
全裸  妓女
Nudity, prostitute...
对不起  心不在焉
Sorry, preoccupied.
豪斯和你说了什么  不是吗
House said something to you, didn't he?
没  他没有
Nope. He didn't.
是有点疯狂  可是
It is a little crazy, though.
我是说...  不是吗
I mean... isn't it?
我是说  看起来不错但他们看起来好像
I mean... things seem to be going great. But they seemed to be going great
12年前就认识了
12 years ago.
优点还是优点
The good things are still good.
她还是那么聪明  有趣  善解人意
She's still smart, funny, gets me.
而且不争强好胜
And she's less competitive.
也许是她变了  或许是我变了
Either she's changed, or I've changed.
可是  不管怎样...
But, either way...
我是不是有点发神经呢
Am I out of my mind?
你永远不知道结局会怎样
You never know what can happen.
还是给彼此一个机会的好
You might as well give it a chance.
好吧
Yeah.
看来你是对的
Looks like you were right.
肿瘤  到处都是
Tumors... dozens of them.
内部  表皮上都是
Inside, and on the surface.
拉近点
Pull in closer.
看到了吗
See that?
那是什么
What is that?
我不知道
I don't know.
但肯定不是癌症
But it's definitely not cancer.
厨房没问题
Kitchen's clean.
卧室也没问题
Bedroom as well.
他医药箱里最危险的东西就是牙线了
Most dangerous thing in his medicine cabinet was dental floss.
那个锁着  钥匙不在钥匙扣上
It's locked, key wasn't on his ring.
说真话  难道你想回去
Do you honestly want to go back
告诉豪斯我们没有查遍他屋子的每一个角落吗
and tell House we didn't check every square inch of this place?
当然不想
Of course not.
我的英雄
My hero.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
一个通往霍格华兹的秘密通道或者是
Either a secret entrance to Hogwarts, or...
我们的骑士  是个巫师
Our Knight... is a witch.
我们的骑士正在进行某种恐怖活动
Our Knight is into some seriously creepy stuff.
他声称只是糖水  但是我们把剩下的送到了实验室化验
He claims it's just sugar water but we sent the rest down to the lab for testing.
你觉得他想毒死自己么
Do you think he poisoned himself?
那不是毒药  要不然我们早就在验血的时候发现了
It's not poison, we would have picked it up in his blood work.
要是在肝脏里慢慢累积起来的就不同了
Not if it collected slowly in his liver.
它会一次性渗入到他的身体系统里
and it all started leaking into his system at once.
这些不是肿瘤的肿瘤
These tumors that aren't tumors,
如果只是充血性肝脏节点状病变呢
What if they're focal hepatic lesions filled with blood?
每次激增都会释放更多的量
Every time one explodes it'd be releasing another dose.
什么的量
Of what?
铅葵
Plumbum nigrum.
你给谁施过法了吗
You putting a hex on someone?
拉丁文  意思是石铅
It's latin, for black lead.
我们的骑士/术士显然也练过炼金术
Our Knight/Warlock apparently also dabbles in alchemy.
铅中毒
Lead poisoning.
癫痫  瘫痪  免疫力差
Seizures, paralysis,weak immune system,
最后会出现  昏迷
and eventually, coma.
在膀胱处取样做活检  你一定会发现铅
Biopsy the cysts, and you'll find your lead.
你觉得我们七点半能到吗
You think we'll make the 7:30?
对不起  如果我不换衣服的话
I'm sorry, if I don't change,
我会觉得自己一晚上都在工作
I'm gonna feel like I'm at work all night.
对  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
有问题吗
Is it a problem?
根本没有
Not at all.
其实如果我们快一点
In fact, if we hurry--
我们七点半肯定到不了
We will definitely not make the 7:30.
反正九点四十还能去
Well, there's always the 9:40.
也许不能
Or not.
你不是应该在医院里吗
Shouldn't you be at the hospital?
如果我包揽了所有的活就不需要手下了  对吧
Wouldn't need a team if I did all the work now, would I?
另外  我还要给你们做晚餐
Plus, I had to make you dinner.
我们有安排了
We have plans.
我敢担保你们的计划肯定尝起来没这么美
I bet your plans don't taste like this.
不要
Don't!
豪斯  不管你脑子里面转的什么
House, whatever it is that you're up to--
我只是想做个好人
I'm trying to be nice.
那天晚上我太孩子气了
What I did the other night was juvenile.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但奶酥太好吃了
The souffle was amazing.
是我妈妈的配方
It's my mom's recipe.
其他的我都是从网上搜来的
Everything else, I got off the Web.
为网络干杯
Here's to the Internet.
因为它我找到了蔬菜炖肉
Where I found the lamb ragout,
而你们找到了彼此再一次地
and you two found each other... Again.
不只是网络
Well, it wasn't just the Internet.
对啊  更多的是离婚  压抑
Yeah, more like divorce, depression,
心理治疗  更多的心理治疗 最后才是网络
therapy, more therapy, and the Internet.
我们就这样在一起了
And here we are.
没错
Exactly.
我们就这样在一起了
And here we are.
我要去趟洗手间
Well, I need to go to the bathroom.
我想你现在应该能独自应对了吧
I think you're old enough, now.
不过如果你希望我跟你一起
But if you would like me to come along with you...
我的意思是  你们俩单独在一起没事吧
I mean, is it safe to leave the two of you?
少来  詹姆斯  够了
Come on, James. Enough, already.
对啊  詹姆斯  我们会和平共处的
Yeah, James,I cook in peace.
好的
Okay.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你是个冷血的女人  把他的心都伤透了
You're a cold-hearted bitch, who ripped his heart out.
为了平复你带给他的伤害我看着他苦苦挣扎了好多年
I watched him struggle for years to overcome the damage you did.
我绝不能就这么让你
And there's no way I'm going to just let you
把他骗回去  再伤害他一次
wheel him back in so you can do it all over again.
那这算什么
And all this?
第二阶段是要了解我的敌人
Phase two of getting to know my enemy.
你看错我了
You're wrong about me.
不过我很高兴詹姆斯不在的时候
But I'm glad now I don't have to pretend to like you,
我不用再假装喜欢你了
except for when James is standing next to me.
我也是
Same here.
唯一的不同是  我比你更长久
Only difference is, I'll outlast you.
开演
And scene.
现在看电影太晚了
Well, it's too late for the movie.
想看看电视吗
Wanna see what's on tv?
当然
Absolutely.
很乐意
Love to.
检查血液或者肝脏活检时并未发现铅
There wasn't any lead present in his blood work. Or liver biopsy.
他的心率和血压越来越不稳定
And his heart rate and BP are getting even more erratic.
我们晚上已经两次通过电击来恢复心率
We had to shock it back into rhythm twice during the night.
那就只剩一件事可做
There's only one thing left to do.
我们在浪费时间
We're waiting our time.
事实上  我已经捡回便宜了
Actually, I've already gotten good value.
我已经告诉过你  这里没有东西 能引起他的任何症状
I told you,there's nothing here that could have caused any of his symptoms.
不对  你告诉我的是  你不能在这里找到
No, you told me that you couldn't find
任何能引起他的症状 的东西
anything here that could becausing the symptoms.
现在我们就能找出点新东西来
And now we're gonna find something new
因为我们也乔装打扮了一下吗
because we're in costume?
我们搜查了每一处  检测了每一样东西
We looked everywhere, tested everything.
威尔森的办事拙劣并不能代表我们跟他一样
Just because Wilson's acting stupid doesn't mean we are.
你觉得他做得不对
Do you think he's making a mistake?
当然
Of course.
不过他早晚会发觉的
But he'll figure it out, sooner or later.
但愿就在几个星期激烈的床上运动之后
Hopefully after a few weeks of great sex.
不入虎穴  焉得虎子
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
威尔森跟我们不一样
Wilson's not like us.
他太关心别人  和他们的感受
He cares too much about people and their feelings.
谢谢你的赞美
Thanks for the compliment.
我们的骑士所扬言的一切法则
The code that our Knight claims to live by,
那些关于光荣和骑士的狗屁精神
all that crap about honor and chivalry.
威尔森天生就那样  这就是为什么他是
Wilson's naturally like that, which is why he's--
一个很棒的人
a great guy.
一个被人玩弄的猎物
A sucker and a target.
所以我们得看着他
So we gotta look out for him.
你闻到了吗
Do you smell that?
是的  这是药店
Yeah, it's the apothecary shop.
而且  福曼和我已经
And yes, Foreman and I already...
有什么事情吗  先生
I cry your pardon, Sir.
你知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
这是薰衣草
Well, that's lavender.
这是蔷薇果
Try rose hips.
都是无害的  谁在乎
Both harmless, who cares?
按他说的  这可能是氰化物
It could be cyanide as far as he knows.
这是什么
How about this?
这只是圣约翰草
It be nothing but St. John's Wort.
又错了  黑哈希
Wrong again. Black cohash.
店主是我叔叔  我不过是刚来当学徒的
My Uncle owns the shop,I just started apprenticing.
有什么大不了的
What the big deal?
喂
Hey!
我刚把那些整理好
I just organized all that.
你知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
一根野生胡萝卜
A wild carrot?
这是铁杉  你这个绣花枕头
It's hemlock, you embossed carbuncle.
那是铁杉吗  你确定吗
That's hemlock? You sure?
你卖给谁了吗
Did you sell it to anyone?
这是毒药  再想想
It's poison, think hard.
只是那么一根而已
It was just one branch.
你卖给了威廉姆先生
You sold it to Sir William?
没有
No.
给国王的
To the King.
这就是你唯一没检查到环境因素
It's the only part of the environment you didn't check.
住在这里的居民
The people living in it.
到底怎么了
What's going on?
为什么不让我们见威廉姆
Why can't we see William?
因为你对他下毒了
Because you poisoned him.
你这个皇家恶棍
Your royal anus.
就是这个
With this.
野生胡萝卜
Wild carrots?
是铁杉
Hemlock.
我要知道你用了多少是怎样调制的
I need to know how much you used and how you prepared it.
是你对威廉姆动了手脚
You did something to William?
不  当然没有
No, of course not!
他还活着
He's still alive.
要是想避免谋杀罪  你还是快点招了
You want to avoid a murder charge, start talking fast.
那个药剂师愿意出庭作证他只把这东西卖给了你
The apothecary's willing to testify that you're the only one he gave it to.
好吧  也许我为了挑战各种 食物而买了那个
Okay, yeah, maybe I bought it for the food challenge,
可我不知道那是铁杉
but I didn't know that was hemlock.
既然是挑战  那为什么只有
If it was for the challenge, then why is wee Willie
小Willie骑士奄奄一息了呢
the only Knight who's dying?
我不知道
I don't know!
我告诉你  我不知道
I'm telling you, I didn't know.
我为什么要伤害威廉姆
Why would I want to hurt William?
至少我能想到一个理由
I can think of at least one reason.
迈尔斯  拜托
Miles, please.
不管发生了什么  把真相说出来吧
Whatever happened, just tell them the truth.
我说的是实话
I am!
我发誓
I swear.
我们对他的血液做了气相色谱分析
We ran a gas chromatography on his blood.
发现了一定量的哌啶类生物碱
Found trace amounts of piperidine alkaloids.
铁杉中的主要致毒成分
The main markers of hemlock intoxication.
好消息是我们弄清楚你的病因了
Well, the good news is we now know what's wrong with you.
坏消息是
The bad news is
你国王的完美形象都是伪装出来的
that your King's precious ideals were just pretend after all.
至少  对他的王后过分亲近的人是这样
At least, when it comes to guys who get too close to his Queen.
这不是真的
It's not true.
我估计你从来没听说这句话吧
I guess you've never heard the expression,
"气相色谱分析仪从不骗人"
"Gas chromatography machines don't lie."
迈尔斯也从不撒谎
Neither does Miles.
他是我认识的最优秀的骑士
He's the best Knight I've ever known.
这就是为什么他会成为国王
It's why he was chosen King.
迈尔斯是极具嫉妒心的白痴
Miles is a jealous idiot.
而你是个纯粹的傻瓜
And you're just an idiot.
好像有点不对劲
Uh, something's wrong.
我们给他洗了胃
We performed a gastric lavage
用了活性炭
and administered activated charcoal,
但他的病情没有好转  反而恶化了
but he's getting worse, not better.
毒素在他体内已经两天了
Well, it's been in his system two days.
他撑了这么久  我们算幸运了
We're lucky he's lasted this long.
如果真是铁杉  他要么早就死了
If it was hemlock, he'd either be dead already
要么就好转了
or getting better with treatment.
确实是铁杉  我们在他的血液中查到的
It's hemlock, we found it in his blood.
他可能是吃了一些铁杉 但这不是他的病因
He may have had some hemlock, but it's not what's killing him.
千万别动手
Don't do it!
不管你在预谋什么
Whatever you're planning,
特别是你还想用手上的那玩意儿
especially if you're gonna use that thing.
天哪
Geez.
这剑还好好呆着石头里呢[亚瑟王]
It was just sitting in a stone.
给你
Here.
你要的这么具体价钱可得高些
It's gonna cost extra, because of the level of detail that you wanted.
有什么猛料吗
Anything good?
当然  我说的是反话
And by good, I, of course, mean bad.
没有  差不多就是你的翻版
Nope, pretty much your typical life.
早婚  离了婚
Married young, got divorced.
老一点后再婚  再离婚了
Married a little less young, got divorced.
除了婚姻  她各方面都很成功
She's been pretty successful in everything she's done, except marriage.
肯定有什么内幕能被我利用
Well, there's gotta be something I can use.
也许吧  不过我没看她的心理医生笔记
Maybe. Didn't read her shrink's notes.
这样似乎不太好
Didn't seem right.
但把它们偷出来就没关系
But stealing them did.
我可不是偷的
Whoa, I didn't steal them.
我有特殊渠道能弄到
I found a way to obtain them.
抱歉  我不是故意要打断你们 你现在有时间吗
Excuse me, I don't mean to interrupt, but you got a minute?
当然
Sure.
你找他啊  好吧  我回避
Oh, him? Yeah, I was just leaving.
小心点  我可有把剑
Careful. I have a sword.
我并不赞同你的话
I don't agree with what you said.
但我能理解你这么说的目的
But I understand why you said it.
我们结婚时很年轻  我们犯了很多错误
We were married young, we both made mistakes,
的确  大部分是我的错
and yes, I did make most of them.
但这都过去十多年了
But that was almost a decade ago.
不好意思 今天是忏悔日吗
I'm sorry, is that the statutory period for soul sucking?
我没要求你喜欢我  豪斯
I'm not asking you to like me, House.
坦白说  我认为你是个混蛋
To be honest, I think you're an ass.
但我们有一点是相同的
But we do have one thing in common.
那就是我们都在乎詹姆斯
We care about James.
那就证明啊
So prove it.
甩了他  再甩一次
And dump him... again.
你总是让人如此难以忍受吗
You're pretty much insufferable all the time, aren't you?
抱歉  继续  没错
Sorry, go on. And, yes.
我们才刚刚重聚  我们也不清楚 今后会怎样发展
We just reconnected, we have no idea where we're headed.
但要问  你能不能给我们
But is it really too much to ask
继续下去的机会  是不是有点多余
that you give us a chance to find out?
我相信  我们会常见面的
I'm sure I'll be seeing you around.
我们成功了
We did it.
其实  是我成功了
Well, I did it.
我们到底做什么了
What exactly did we do?
是你做什么了
You do?
他肝脏上的并不是节点状病变
These aren't focal hepatic lesions on his liver,
而是紫癜造成的肝脏损伤
they're peliosis hepitus lesions.
再加上心率不齐
Which in combination with an erratic heart rate,
这通常是
usually indicates--
心内膜炎
endocarditis.
心脏瓣膜感染
Infection on his heart valve.
滥用促蛋白合成类固醇的两大症状
Two major symptoms of anabolic steroid abuse.
不  他不会
No, he wouldn't.
横纹肌溶解是第三个症状
And the rhabdo makes the third.
我们的病人是个瘾君子
Our patient's a juicer.
古老的毒药加速了现代毒药 造成的损伤
Ancient poison accelerated the damage of the modern poison.
开始治疗  把国王放了
Start treatment, let the King out of the tower.
感觉怎样
How are you feeling?
很惭愧
Ashamed.
你是该感到惭愧
You should be.
你宁愿选择比武的胜利
You'll compromise your ideals to win a fight,
也不愿争取心上人的垂青
but not to go for the woman you love.
那只是场游戏
That was a game.
而不是现实生活
Not real life.
-我没有  -伤害任何人吗
- I didn't-- - hurt anyone?
这话你倒是跟夏伦去说啊
Try telling that to Shannon.
或许她在你床边哭泣的时候 我错过了什么
Or maybe I missed something while she was crying by your bed.
爱人的心不是赢来的
You don't need to win anyone's heart.
你应该问她愿不愿意将心交给你
You just need to ask for it.
迈尔斯是个好人
Miles is a great guy.
他富有  聪明  待她好
He's rich, smart, treats her well.
她和他在一起会很幸福
She's gonna have a great life with him.
而我呢
But me?
为了她  我尽我所有
Well, I'd do everything I could for her,
即使我再努力  也无法做到
but even at my best, it wouldn't be much.
她应该过最好的生活
And she deserves the best.
我想  我愿意看着她幸福 即使这意味着我会很痛苦
I guess I'd rather she be happy even if it means I'm not.
我想豪斯说对了
I guess House was right about that, too.
什么
What?
你真的是个傻瓜
You really are an idiot.